The next words are about global and Taiwan environmental issues
接下來的話是講全球與台灣的環境議題
Then the global word is nothing more than what everyone has often heard from before to now is the greenhouse effect and the hole in the ozone layer.
那全球的話就不外乎大家從以前到現在常聽到的就是溫室效應還有臭氧層的破洞
Little is known about the spread of hazardous industrial waste
那有害事業廢棄物的擴散這些大家都比較少知道
Everyone mainly knows that greenhouse gases rise and then cause
大家都主要是知道溫室氣體上升然後造成
Destruction of the balance of biological ecology
生物生態的平衡造成破壞
That's roughly the case
那這一塊的話大致上是這樣
In terms of Taiwan, the main problem for us in Taiwan is that
那台灣的話主要我們台灣的問題點就是
The reason why the waste is dumped indiscriminately is because the land in Taiwan is narrow and densely populated.
亂倒廢棄物為什麼亂倒廢棄物就是因為我們台灣的土壤地狹人稠
Then there is
然後就是
There is no way to deal with a lot of waste, which leads to
許多廢棄物沒辦法去做處理所以導致
Many manufacturers collect
許多家廠商收集
Business waste of each household or garbage of the general public
各家的事業廢棄物或者是一般民眾的垃圾
To save these costs then go
為了省這些成本然後去
Without the treatment of the equipment
不經就是沒有經過設備的處理
then go mess
然後去亂倒
The current situation in Taiwan is
台灣目前的狀況是
Dumping waste and looting sand and gravel
亂倒廢棄物還有盜採砂石
The illegal mining of sand and gravel will cause some damage to the soil and ecological problems.
盜採砂石會造成土壤的一些破壞還有生態的問題點
I've been paying more attention to this one recently.
那這一塊的話在近期還蠻注重這一塊的
Then we now see that there is a picture with two pictures above
那我們現在看到上面有一張有兩張圖
This drawing of him
他這一張的畫圖
this one
這一張
The words here are mainly like this one
這邊的話主要是像這一張
The second photo is the one on the bridge and the last one is also the main one
第二張照片的話就是那個在橋頭這邊還有最後一張也都是主要
Near the bridgehead, there are a lot of unscrupulous businessmen.
附近橋頭那這一塊的話就是經過很多不法的商人
Receive some rubbish littering this piece this photo is in that
接收一些廢棄物亂棄置這一塊這一張照片的話是在那個
Qiaotou's pen show community
橋頭的筆秀社區
If there are residents nearby
那如果附近有居民
If our employees live there, I don't know if you know this place.
就是我們員工有住那邊的話我不知道你們知不知道這一塊地方
In this case, there are some unscrupulous businessmen who take over the waste of public institutions.
那這一塊的話就是有一些不肖業者接收事業單位的廢留
If it is not processed and then placed directly here, the scope of his influence is quite large.
不經過處理然後直接放到這邊那他影響的範圍還蠻大的
Then let's watch the movie
那我們先看一下片
If the comparison bridge just now is here, if the waste is dumped
他剛剛那個比較橋頭就是這邊的話如果被亂倒廢棄物的話
This is which manufacturer to look for, that is, if the institution entrusts this manufacturer
這個是要找哪一家廠商就是如果事業單位委託這一家廠商
To clean the waste stream of sludge, if this waste manufacturer disposes of it indiscriminately
去做汙泥那個廢流的清潔他這家廢棄物廠商如果亂棄置的話
If the EPA catches it, it will be pushed back
這個環保局抓到的話是往回推
Including business units and processing units and removal units are subject to penalties
包括事業單位以及處理單位以及清除單位都要被受罰則
Then this piece of land is going to go through everyone, that is, there will be a
那這一塊土地就是要經過大家去就是那個會去有一個
Jointly delegated responsibility here
共同委託責任這邊都要
Whoever caused the accident is responsible and who has to pay to deal with it, so there are still more problems in Taiwan.
誰肇事誰負責誰要出錢去做處理所以是目前正在台灣還 多一些問題點的
The concept of environmental protection is to reduce why there are environmental regulations
那環境保護的概念就是說為了要減為什麼會有環境法規這塊
In order to protect the environment, the main thing is to reduce that
為了要做環境的保護就是主要是減少那個
To reduce or avoid the burden and harm of the environment, it is necessary to take some measures and behaviors
減少或避免環境的負擔及危害所以會才做一些措施以及行為
The first is to rule out environmental damage that has occurred or to mitigate the damage that has occurred
第一個就是排除現在已出現的環境的損害或者去減輕現在已經發生
The one that is harmful, let him reduce some of the harmfulness, and then take some precautions
有危害性的那個讓他減低一些危害性那經過一些預防
measures for the improvement of the future environment that ultimately achieves that environment
的措施未來的環境的改善那最終達到那個環境
and sustainable development of resources
及資源的永續發展
The word in this one is that Errenxi. Do you know where Errenxi is?
那這一張的話是那個二仁溪那大家知道二仁溪在哪裡嗎
Or the Errenxi Incident or the Green Oyster Incident
或者是二仁溪事件綠牡蠣事件
Does anyone know? Yes, some people just nod their heads.
有人知道嗎對啊有些人點頭就知道
Because of this piece, he is the same as before in Taiwan in the 1970s
因為這一塊的話他就是一樣以前在台灣在1970
In 2009, Taiwan happened to be developing economically, and then it happened to be searching for some foreign countries.
年的時候台灣剛好是經濟發展嗎然後剛好是搜尋國外的一些
Scrap metal scraps were used to make some heavy metals in the refining.
廢五金下腳料來拿來做一些提煉裡面的重金屬那當時的
The equipment and technology have not developed yet, so the current unscrupulous businessman is directly in that Errenxi
設備還有技術沒有發展所以當下那個不肖業者直接在那個二仁溪
At the junction of Tainan and Kaohsiung, there is an Erren Stream directly on the riverside for cleaning.
台南這一塊跟高雄的交界帶有一條二仁溪直接在河畔那邊做清洗
To extract heavy metals, after refining heavy metals, if you burn them, you will
來提煉重金屬那提煉完之後重金屬提煉的話你燃燒你就會
He released heavy metals and some poisons directly in the river to do some cleaning
釋出重金屬還一些毒害物他都直接在河裡去做一些清洗
Then over time, the green oysters will absorb these heavy metals and become green oysters.
然後久而久之就造成綠牡蠣去吸收這些重金屬造成就是變成綠牡蠣的狀況
That
那
After this one stream has been polluted by these heavy metals so far
這一個溪經過這些的重金屬污染之後到目前為止
It is still very serious because many harmful substances cause the entire surrounding environment
還是很嚴重因為許多的一些有害物質造成那個整個那個周遭的環境
The damaged one is the current one that he is still doing sorting out and the current one.
受到破壞這個就是目前他還在做整理這樣的跟目前的那個
The condition of Houjinxi is similar.
後勁溪的狀況差不多
Now is
現在就是
Mainly this problem
主要是這個問題點
That is, Taiwan is developing now, and sustainable development is because of the current
那就是台灣現在就是在發展說永續發展就是因為目前
Are all resources taken from nature? Then the resources will be exhausted.
資源都是取之大自然嗎然後資源一定會會消耗殆盡的
How to go
那如何去
Prevention of this problem used to be a linear economy and now it is to promote a circular economy
預防這問題以前是以線性經濟然後現在是推廣循環經濟
Then what is linear economy, I will talk about the number of the one in this picture later.
那何謂線性經濟的話的後面會再講一下這一張圖有多少的那個的那個
If the resources will be left to the next generation, this one is the fastest at present, and then in 100 years, the whole
資源會留給下一代這一張的話目前最快是現況然後在100年後整個
If there are heavy metals, there is absolutely no such thing, so now I put some
重金屬類的話就完全就是沒有的所以現在把一些
Reusable waste bag reuse reduces economic exhaustion
可以再利用的廢棄物袋重複使用減少經濟的耗盡
This is a schematic diagram of the cycle between the linear economy and the circular economy.
這張是那個線性經濟跟循環經濟的循環示意圖
In the past, the raw materials came directly
以前的話就是直接原物料原物料過來
After the raw materials are obtained, the resources are added to the production and then consumed
原物料取得資源之後然後加生產之後再來消費
After consumption, give it to consumers to use, and then throw it away after consumers use it
消費完給消費者去做使用然後消費者使用完之後就拿去丟棄
There is no action to reuse at all, and the current promotion is
完全沒有做再利用的動作現在的推廣就是
After the produced product is used by the consumer, it is made into
把那個生產出來的經過消費者這邊所使用後就是把它做
Recycling and recycling do the action of refining separately and then the current situation of the economic zone
循環再利用另外做提煉的動作然後那個經濟帶現況
In terms of sustainable development, the revolving fund he talked about, in terms of NXP, our current
那永續發展的話跟他講的那個循環基金以恩智浦來講的話我們的目前的
raw material for some waste
一些廢棄物的原物料
There are currently
目前有針對那一個
The waste compression molding glue goes to some of the manufacturers to do the recycling and then
廢壓模膠去找一些的那個廠商去做循環然後再
Doing that Portland cement is like that
做那個矽酸水泥就是像那個
The kind of concrete on the road
一般馬路上那種水泥地
Then or like the plastic that the company currently produces is to do it twice
然後或者像目前那個廠公司有產出的塑膠就是把它做2次
A plastic particle prepared for the second time
二次己配的一個塑膠粒子
to reuse
去做再利用
If the EPA's policy on that environment is related to the law just mentioned, this is
那環保局針對那個環境的政策有針對剛剛所講的那個法條來講的話這是
There is an air pollution law, a water pollution law, a waste disposal law, and a noise control law.
有設定那個空污法還有水污法還有廢棄物清理法一定噪音管制法
In fact, there are quite a number of laws and regulations, and they are mainly aimed at these items, which are closely related to factories.
那其實還蠻多項的法條然後主要是針對這幾項是跟工廠息息相關的
Air pollution prevention and control
空汙防治的話在空污汙染的
By definition, there is one or more pollutants or mixtures in the outdoor atmosphere that cause
定義上就是在戶外大氣裡有一種或多種的污染物或混合物然後導致
Affect the life and property of humans, animals and plants, and unreasonably interfere with people
影響到人類及動植物的生命財產以及不合理得干擾到人
There are two types of air pollution: one is a mobile source of pollution, and the second is a fixed source of pollution.
那汙染源的話空氣污染有分兩種一種是較移動式污染源第二種是叫做固定式污染源
Mobile pollution sources are nothing more than cars, motorcycles and trains.
移動式污染源就不外乎就是汽車摩托車還有火車那些
Stationary pollution sources are the more common ones, which are the stationary pollution sources of some wastes emitted by factories.
固定式污染源就是比較常見就是工廠工廠所排放的一些廢棄物固定污染源
If these pollution sources are to be discharged, they will have to go through some equipment and technologies.
那這些污染源的話要如果排放出出來的話就要經過一些設備以及技術
Go out and make improvements
出去做改善
then reach 1
然後達到1個
Only qualified range values ​​can be used for emissions
合格範圍值才可以做排放
If the company is concerned, the waste of the company is mainly due to the gaseous pollutants and the
那一公司來講的話公司的那個廢棄的話是主要是在那個氣狀污染物以及
Particulate pollutants and toxic pollutants which gases are that
粒狀污染物還有那個毒性污染物哪些氣體是那個
How to deal with sulfide sulfur oxides, sulfuric acid and sodium nitrate
硫化物硫氧化物以及硫酸還有硝酸鈉這些怎麼做處理就是經過
that scrubber
那個洗滌塔
The principle of the scrubber is to use physical absorption and chemical absorption to have that gas
洗滌塔的原理就是用物理吸收以及化學吸收就是有那個氣體的
Solubility in liquid dissolve some gas in that water and do
液體中的溶解度把一些氣體溶解在那個水上然後去做
The action of the cycle washes the contaminants down, and after the fine wash
循環的動作把那個污染物洗下來精洗完之後
The clean gas is discharged, and the discharge is what you want to discharge, if you want to deal with that
乾淨的氣體就排放出去那排放出去就是你要排放的話要處理到了那個
Regulations define the standard that can discharge
法規定義的標準那才可以排放
If you are caught by the EPA, you will be fined directly
如果被環保局抓到話就直接開罰
As you just said about the emission of exhaust gas, the Environmental Protection Agency will set some emission standards for that.
那剛剛講的話那個排放廢氣的話環保局針對一些那個排放的標準
And fixed pollution source permit system to set up automatic continuous monitoring
以及固定污染源地許可制度設置自動連續監測
That automatic continuous monitoring is to detect that
那自動連續監測就是檢測說
How much waste does the equipment in your factory emit and then there is another
你的這個工廠的設備排放多少量廢棄物出去然後還有一
the amount of pollutants and then go
汙染物多少量然後去
charge some fees to control
徵收一些費用去做管制
His words are that the waste is closely related to everyone.
他這項的話是那個廢棄物跟大家比較息息相關
This is the general residents and people will produce some waste that the definition of waste is to say
這是一般的居民和人民都會產生一些廢棄物那廢棄物的定義是說
Abandoned, or the one that was originally unusable or that
被拋棄者或者是那個原本是沒辦法再用或者是說
He has been unable to use the existing technology or the economic value without the market to do it again and again.
他已經沒辦法用現有的技術或不具市場的經濟價值去做再重複在
There are two types of recycling called waste.
再利用稱為廢棄物的話有有分兩種類別
One is general waste and the other is business waste
一種是一般廢棄物另外一種是事業廢棄物
General waste is waste other than business waste What is business waste?
一般廢棄物就是事業廢棄物以外的廢棄物什麼叫事業廢棄物就是
The factory that is open
有營業的那個工廠
Industrial waste can be divided into harmful and harmless
事業廢棄物有分說有害跟無害
That is, there are hazardous industrial waste and general industrial waste Hazardous industrial waste for each
就是有有害事業廢棄物及一般事業廢棄物有害事業廢棄物針對每個
The first characteristic of the waste is the PH value or its ignition point.
那個廢棄物的特性第一個就是PH值或者他的那個燃點去做
Classification
分類
or heavy metal content
或是裡面的重金屬的含量
How to remove some of the waste produced by the factory? The Environmental Protection Agency
那工廠所產出的一些廢棄物如何去做清除那這個環保局
There are also some laws and regulations to be done to ask for how to do it.
也有訂一些就是法條去做去要求規範之說如何去做
Effectively disposing of business units is NXP's garbage in terms of NXP
有效的處理事業單位的話就是以恩智浦來講是恩智浦的垃圾
will process or reuse this part
會處理經過處理或者是往再利用這部分
There are self-processing and joint processing, and clearing processing is also entrusted. The current situation here
有分自行處理以及共同處理還委託清除處理那這邊目前的話
They are all entrusting the removal manufacturer and the processing manufacturer to do some legal actions.
都是委託那個清除廠商以及處理廠商去做一些合法的動作
Then these words will go through some
那這些的話還會經過一些
other competent authority
其他的那個主管機關去做
Supervision
監督力度
action requested
要求去做處理的動作
If this is garbage, if the garbage bag factory is cleared out, it will be
他這個是垃圾清出去的話垃圾袋工廠清出去的話就要
This factory needs a clean-up plan and an Internet declaration of garbage to go out is to do Internet
這家工廠要一個清理計畫書以及網路申報垃圾出去就是要做網路
The online declaration will link to the EPA website and see how much your company produces every day
網路申報是會連結到環保署的網站然後看你這一家公司每天產多
She will keep track of how much rubbish and how much rubbish to remove, to avoid saying that some unscrupulous businessmen will take some rubbish
多少個垃圾清多少垃圾她都會隨時追蹤避免說有些不肖業者會把一些垃圾
I cleaned it out and then I didn't follow the rules and discarded it indiscriminately, just like that
清出去然後沒有沒有照規矩來直接亂棄置就剛剛像那個
The situation in the pen show community in Qiaotou will be completely unknown, so he will
橋頭那個筆秀社區那個狀況一樣完全會查不到所以他會
against
針對
Business units, clearing manufacturers and processing manufacturers will make an online declaration plus clearing manufacturers if they are in
事業單位以及清除廠商以及處理廠商會去做一個網路申報加上清除廠商如果在
After NXP cleared the garbage, he went out to the factory and asked for a GPS tracking
恩智浦清完垃圾之後他出去出廠要一個GPS的追蹤
He will check whether this route has been properly dealt with after reaching the disposal site.
他會針對這個路線有沒有到達處理場之後有沒有做好妥善的處理
The processing is divided into the entrusted processing and joint processing that everyone is talking about.
處理的話有分大家所講的委託處理還有共同處理
And reusing cross-border processing is something like
還有再利用越境處理就是像
Taiwan's garbage is sent to third countries or other countries for disposal, just like that
台灣的垃圾都送到第三國家或是其他國家去那邊做處理就像剛剛那
The Errenxi incident is the situation in Taiwan.
那個什麼那個二仁溪事件就是台灣的狀況就是
Receive garbage from European and American countries for removal
接收歐美國家垃圾來做清除
have these three
有這三項
If the waste removal business unit wants to remove waste, it must set up the waste person in charge
在那個廢棄物的清除事業單位如果要清除廢棄物要設置那個廢棄物專責人員
Then in NXP, there is a third item in this and
那在恩智浦的話是有符合這裡面的第三項以及
Item 4, Item 5 and Item 6 should be assigned special personnel
第4項第5項以及第6項這些都要設置專責人員
to control, manage and supervise
去做管控,管理及督導
This article is the criterion for the determination of a considerable duty of care for business entrustment and clean-up
那個這一條的話是事業委託清理之相當注意義務認定準則
That rule is based on 30 rules. If something like the one just now is thrown away, then tell him about it.
那個定準則是依據30條如果像剛剛那個有如果被亂棄置然後就跟他講
Institutions, removal manufacturers and processing manufacturers must be jointly and severally responsible for removal
事業單位以及清除廠商還有處理廠商都要連帶責任去做清除
Then this cost is all business units. For example, if NXP entrusts a manufacturer to dispose of it indiscriminately
那這個費用都是事業單位例如假設恩智浦如果委託一家廠商他亂棄置的話
If the inspection department of the Environmental Protection Agency comes to find out
如果環保局那個檢查科來來查到
If you go to the source to check, including NXP and the removal manufacturer, you must go to the site
往源頭查的話包括恩智浦還有清除廠商都要到現場
take care of the land
把這些土地做好妥善處理
There are also some penalties here.
那這一塊也是都有一些罰則
That is before the cleaning of the business unit if the garbage is to be removed
那個在垃圾如果要清除之前在事業單位的清理前
Do some classified storage and self-inspection in the factory
做一些分類的儲存以及廠內自主巡查
If there is a special person to do it, we need to ask each unit to do a good job in classification.
有那個專責人員去做的那個要去要求各個單位去做好分類的
If the action is not properly classified, it will cause the removal of the manufacturer to clear out the problem.
動作如果沒有做好分類導致那個清除廠商清出去有問題那個很冤望
This is the source business, that is, the business unit. If you are looking for the removal manufacturer
這是源頭事業就是事業單位這邊如果你要找那個清除廠商
When the cleanup is done, a written contract will be written.
做清除的時候會去寫個書面契約
The written contract should be very detailed, including whether the manufacturer you are looking for has the technology to handle it or whether he has the equipment
書面契約要寫很細包括你找的廠商他有沒有技術可以去處理或者他有沒有設備
capable of doing these actions
有能力做這些動作
Properly dispose of after clearing you have to provide one he provides one to dispose of properly
清除之後妥善處理你也要提供一個他提供一個妥善處理
Clearing the file will bring the EPA for future reference
清除文件這個會帶那個環保局來做備查的動作
The specification for the removal and disposal of industrial waste storage means that
事業廢棄物儲存的清除處理的規範就是說
The same is that you can't let my garbage fly when you suddenly add your garbage bags for storage
一樣就是分類儲存突然後加上你的垃圾袋儲存的時候你不能讓我垃圾飛揚
or spills, seeps or contaminates the ground or emits a foul odor
或溢散滲出或污染地面或發出惡臭
Air pollution laws are affected by flying and spreading odor
飛揚溢散惡臭這些事會影響到空汙法
seeps the water that pollutes the ground that trashes his impact on pollution regulations
滲出汙染到地面那些垃圾的水他的影響到污染法規
These are closely related and more troublesome, so it is better to store them
這些都是息息相關的比較麻煩所以要儲存比較好
Including your garbage storage, you have to go through whether it has compatibility or not. What is compatibility?
包括你垃圾存儲的話你要經過他有沒有相容性何謂相容性就
That is, if two different substances are mixed together, will some explosions occur?
就是他兩個不一樣的物質混在一起會不會發生一些爆炸產生一些
Hazardous gases, be careful with these
有害物氣體啊這些都要注意
The storage location is the same, and the container facilities must be marked in Chinese.
儲存的地點一樣容器設施都是要用中文標示區讓那個
Discarders do a good job of distinguishing not to cause incompatibility or that
丟棄者做好分辨不要造成說不相容或者是那個
There are some problems with garbage
垃圾有產生一些問題點
The prevention and control of hazardous industrial waste is almost the same as the storage regulations for general industrial waste.
防治有害事業廢棄物也是差不多是跟一般事業廢棄物的儲存的規定都是一樣的
If he looks at the photo, he thinks it's actually fine
這一張的話他看照片會覺得其實還好
But this is actually he
但這個其實他這個是
1 box is how many inches
1箱是幾吋的
This is an organic solvent, which organic solvent, you empty the bucket
這個是有機溶劑啊哪有機溶劑你空桶
In terms of occupational safety law
以職安法來講的話
If there is solvent in it, use a drain pan
裡面盛裝溶劑的話是要用盛漏盤
The one from the anti-leakage treatment plant is already empty, but why is this one still needed?
防洩漏處理廠那個啊已經雖然是空桶但為什麼為什麼這一張還要
Take it out and tell everyone about it because he still has some residual fluid in it
拍出來跟大家講因為他裡面還有一些殘液
This piece is considered hazardous industrial waste because it is the organic solvent or the organic solvent.
這塊的話是算是有害事業廢棄物因為他是有機溶劑那有機溶劑的那個
If the flash point is greater than 60 degrees
那個閃火點如果大於60度的話
He is classified in Hazardous Industrial Waste He can't be like this
他是歸類在有害事業廢棄物他不能這樣子
He's trying to tell him that it can't be that
他是要跟他講的說不能不能那個
Dispose of it indiscriminately, or paste that Chinese sign to sort it out.
亂棄置啊或者是要貼那個中文標示去做好分類
This one is that one
這一張的話是那個
If this picture is an environmental protection cockroach, it is hypothetical
環保蟑螂的話如果這一張就是假設
The family here has land, or that house is to be rented out to others
在座的家人有土地啊或者是那一個房子要出租給別人
Pay attention to your own safety. Some people will rent it out after renting it.
要自己注意安全注意一下有些人承租來之後會把
Accept some waste and then dispose of it indiscriminately. If it is found here, the landlord must deal with it.
接受一些廢棄物然後亂棄置被查到這邊都是要有房東去做處理
The removal of the manufacturer in the business unit has to do the removal.
事業單位那個那個清除廠商就要去做清除的動作
Take a look at the video
好看一下影片
Like he just said, a garbage is cleared out and he charges
像他剛剛講的一個垃圾清出去他收費
20,000 to 30,000 He will litter the garbage in order to save this money
20000至30000他為了省這個錢就會把垃圾亂丟亂丟的
If it is found that there is some joint responsibility, including the landlord and that
如果被查到相對有一些連帶責任包括地主還有那個
The total money for clearing and transporting manufacturers is tens of millions. Many manufacturers do this for this
清運廠商的錢總共是好好幾千萬了很多廠商為了這
It is the processing fee, which is to spend equipment to process and save this little money
就是處理費這是花設備去處理然後省這個小錢
turn into spending the big bucks
變成花這些大錢
At present, there are quite a lot of these situations in Taiwan, but how to catch them can't be done because
目前台灣還蠻多這些現況只是怎麼抓做不完因為
It is very profitable to do waste
做廢棄物很好賺我每一家公司給你收兩萬塊一次收100家那我
How much is to be received in a month and do not need to be dealt with, then there are many such problems.
一個月要收進帳多少不用去處理啊那就很多這種問題點
That's why the garbage we just mentioned is cleared out, and many GPS homes don't check it.
所以才會剛剛所講的垃圾清出去有的GPS很多家也是不會去查
There are only a few people in the inspection department of so many environmental protection bureaus.
廠商那麼多家環保局的抓不完稽查科才幾個人而已
The big problem is that this is the morality of our own people
問題很大要靠這是我們自己人民的那個道德觀
make some improvements
去做一些改善
The waste disposal law If you are punished by the waste disposal law, these are criminal penalties
廢棄物清理法如果你廢棄物清理法的罰則這些是有刑責
Administrative law is fortunate, administrative law is not known to everyone, it is just fines
行政法還好行政法不是大家都知道只是罰款而已
If it involves the criminal law, it is really serious. What does it mean to involve the criminal law?
罰錢了事如果牽扯到刑法那真的是比較嚴重何謂牽扯到刑法
That is, if your garbage affects people and kills people, you will be sentenced to that
就是如果你的垃圾而影響到人就是致人於死的話會判那個
Life imprisonment or more than seven years
無期徒刑或七年以上
30 million or less in prison
有期徒刑三千萬以下如果有傷害致重傷者
More than three years but less than ten years, more than 20,250,000, these words use influence
三年以上十年以下兩千多萬兩千五這些的話用影響
If it goes to the human body or the environment, it is almost always a fine to be arrested, not to say that the manufacturer
到人體或環境的話幾乎都是要罰錢抓去關不是說廠商
People from public institutions should also be arrested and detained unless your institution is powerful enough to have a relationship with the government.
事業單位的人也要抓去關除非你事業單位的夠有力跟政府有
You don't have to shut it down, anyway, there is a situation
關係你就不用去關了反正有現況有一個
For example, there is an event of XX light like this
例如有一個XX光的事件就是這樣
If you have anything better with the government, then you won't put people in private.
你跟政府有什麼比較好的話就是不會把私底下的人
If you want to dispose of your rubbish, you need to store it properly and as mentioned earlier.
你垃圾要那個棄置的話就是剛剛所講要好好的儲存及
These are some regulations to be done well
清除的處理這些都是要做好的一些規定
Let's take a look at some garbage in Kaohsiung that is currently in Taiwan.
在我們看一下這個目前台灣的就是在高雄的一些垃圾
The scavenger manufacturer and some unscrupulous operators dispose of it indiscriminately, mainly at the bridgehead of Fengshan.
那個清除廠商還有一些不肖業者亂棄置主要是在鳳山橋頭
And that Renwu Gangshan, there are mostly Qishan
還有那個仁武岡山那邊居多還有旗山
watch the video
看一下影片
I will talk about how the Environmental Protection Agency conducts statistics, and if the garbage is to be sent out
我講一下環保局怎麼去統計都講如果垃圾要送出
Go to the Internet to declare for each business unit
到那個網路申報針對每個事業單位
Destruction of the environment is even more abhorrent. Starting this March, there are seven in Kaohsiung
破壞環境更可惡了今年三月開始在高雄有七個
The vacant land of the State-owned Assets Supervision and Administration Bureau has been dumped by the tenant, and the cleaning fee for waste disposal is as high as 1.1 billion yuan
國有財產署的空地都被承租人亂倒廢棄物處理的清理費高達11億元
I am afraid that the whole people have to pay the bill again.
恐怕又是要全民買單了為什麼業者是這樣無所不用其極的亂到呢原因是
There are 2,000,000 tons of general industrial waste sent to landfills in Taiwan every year, but there are only two private enterprises
台灣一年要送到掩埋場的一般事業廢棄物就有2000000噸但民間只有兩間對外
The capacity of the operating landfill is less than one million tons, and these wastes have nowhere to be buried.
營運的掩埋場這容量只剩不到百萬頓了這一些廢棄物都無處可埋
Now, the hillside where we stand under our feet is made up of 2,000 tons of rubbish. You can see this hillside.
現在我們腳底下站的這邊山坡的地是有2000噸的垃圾所組成可以看到這一個山坡地
There are gravel, wires, glass, and tiles inside, and it has not been cleaned up until now.
裡面呢有碎石有電線有玻璃有磁磚到現在都還沒有清理
There's grass growing on it, let him stink
上面都長草了任由他發臭
In May last year, residents of this hillside in Qishan protested against smoldering garbage
去年5月旗山這片山坡地垃圾悶燒居民抗議
The suspect rented state-owned land but littered the Kaohsiung Environmental Protection Bureau. Statistics from the Kaohsiung Environmental Protection Bureau have 7 state-owned property offices since 2013.
嫌犯租用國有地卻亂丟垃圾高雄環保局統計2013年到現在有7處國有財產署
The waste was maliciously discarded by the industry, but the landowner's office did not deal with it. Today, the cost is 1.1 billion yuan.
遭到業者惡意棄置廢棄物但地主國產署都不處理代為今日費用11億元
Finally, at the end of July this year, in order to avoid breeding vector mosquitoes, the Environmental Protection Bureau first began to clear and transport them on behalf of
終於在今年7月底為了怕孳生病媒蚊環保局首先開始代為清運
It took 20 days to clear the 400 tons of waste plastic mixture at the junction of Daliao and Fengshan, and it cost 1,900,000 yuan.
光是大寮鳳山交界這一塊被傾倒400噸廢棄塑膠混合物要花20天清除費用1900000元
Environmentally friendly cockroaches are everywhere
環保蟑螂無所不在
Good factory but encounter environmental protection cockroach rental
好好工廠卻碰上環保蟑螂租用
Qiaotou District Prosecutor's Office seized 12 cases of 4,266 metric tons of garbage in March, costing 30 to 68 million yuan
橋頭地檢署三月查獲12例4266公噸垃圾清除費用3000到6800萬元
Why did Taiwan become an abandoned paradise? 25 abandoned cases were found in 2016
到底為何台灣變成棄置天堂2016年查到25件棄置案
100 metric tons were stolen near Taichung high-speed rail, forming a 120-meter-long 14-meter-high garbage mountain
台中高鐵附近被偷盜100公噸形成長120公尺14公尺高的垃圾山
According to the statistics of the Environmental Protection Agency of the year, it needs to send 2.1 million tons of waste to the landfill.
清運費達一億六千萬元根據當年環保署統計需送至掩埋場一般事廢兩百一十萬噸到
2.56 million tons, but there are only two private burial capacity left in the country, 410,000 tons.
兩百五十六萬噸但民間只有兩對外掩埋容量剩410000噸全國近
Forty thousand waste management businesses store 710,000 tons of sludge and 190,000 tons of slag
四萬家廢棄物列管事業儲存710000噸汙泥爐渣十九萬噸
However, the cases of illegal industrial waste disposal are increasing year by year
但非法事業廢棄物棄置案卻逐年攀升
106 years of illegal disposal of industrial waste nationwide
106年全國非法棄置事業廢棄物
A total of 26 cases were transferred for investigation and handling
而被移送偵辦辦案件總共26件
A total of 19.37 million metric tons of industrial waste was declared
事業廢棄物申報量共1937萬公噸
There are some business operators who are greedy for this and this benefit.
有一些業者為了這個貪圖這個這個利益的
He couldn't have sent this to a disposal plant and then disposed of it illegally
他不可能這個送到處理廠然後咧而非法棄置
If you want to set up a new landfill, there will be strong resistance from local residents
想設置新掩埋場都會受到當地居民強烈抗爭
In 2016, the waste disposal law was revised, and the fines soared from below 15 million yuan to below 30 million yuan
2016年 廢棄物清理法修法 罰金從 1500萬元以下飆到3000萬以下
High fines seem to be unable to stop environmental cockroaches rampant
高額罰款卻似乎擋不住環保蟑螂橫行
In the end, the problem lies in the lack of landfills. How to review it has also become a hot potato for the government
最終問題出在掩埋場不足 該如何檢討也成為政府的燙手山芋
He just talked about the problem with that landfill, if the landfill
他剛剛有講到那個那個掩埋場的問題點掩埋場的話就
Taiwan is running out of places to store it. If you are looking for a place to bury it,
台灣已經快沒有地方可以儲存你要找一個地去做掩埋的話其實
It's very troublesome because you have to go through some processes of environmental impact assessment by some government units before you can be willing to do it
很麻煩因為還要經過一些政府單位的環評的一些流程才可以讓你願意去做
These garbage are buried for hundreds of years and tens of thousands of years, so he can let you do the burial after these assessments.
這些垃圾埋下去是好幾百年後幾萬年的所以他經過這些評估才可以讓你做掩埋
As for the landfill, if you find some land, there are some places
那掩埋場的話你找土地有些有些地方的話
How big is the land to be assessed
地要多大要評估
Then again that
再來的話那個
For example, our company NXP's sludge removal is currently looking for that
例如我們的公司恩智浦的汙泥清出去目前是找那個
But Lin Wei, he is now because the landfill is getting less and less and the price has been rising
可林衛他現在就是因為掩埋場越來越少價錢一直在攀升
Many, many manufacturers are just messing around for this landfill.
許多很多家廠商就是為了這掩埋場的事情直接亂倒
He won't be willing to spend so much money to deal with this garbage. In fact, the future problems will be endless.
他不會願意花那麼多錢去處理這些垃圾其實未來的問題會成層出不窮
There will always be problems, but in the future I don't know how to solve it anyway, how will this government solve it
都一直會有問題的只是未來我也不知道要怎麼解決反正這個政府怎麼解決
Does everyone know the CPP? McDonald's, or is it?
卜蜂大家都知道卜蜂嗎麥當勞啊或者是
Major manufacturers use this chicken nugget or chicken
各大廠商都用這家的雞塊或是雞肉
This is their biggest thing, why did the boss come out and apologize because the sludge was disposed of indiscriminately
這個是他們最大的就是老總為什麼要出來道歉因為汙泥亂棄置
That in Changhua is for manufacturers and manufacturers to save this money
那個在彰化為了廠商廠商為了省這個錢
In order to save this money, they directly cleared the manufacturer and cleared it out without arriving.
他們為了省這個錢直接清除廠商清出去沒有到
The sludge treated by the treatment plant is divided into some harmful sludge and biological sludge, which are the most difficult to treat.
處理廠處理污泥有分一些有害汙泥和生物汙泥最難處理的
Harmful sludge is quite simple, just find a place to bury it and that's it
有害汙泥還蠻簡單的只是找個地埋一埋就這樣
For biological sludge, you have to spend more money on equipment to remove these sludges.
生物汙泥你還要多花一些設備的錢去做把這些汙泥去除掉
But he just poured the money directly into the farmland in Changhua to save the money.
但他就是為了省這筆錢直接倒在那個彰化這邊農田
Why was it discovered that there were some farmers nearby
為什麼被發現越附近都有一些農民啊那個種田後來的為什麼旁邊
pile of dirty things
一堆髒東西
The EPA went to the source to find out that they were trying to avoid the money
環保局往源頭去查到是說就是他們為了規避這個錢
To avoid this processing fee and then just dispose of it indiscriminately to save these costs
規避這個處理費然後就是亂棄置要省這些費用
to the whole
鬧到整個
Everyone in Taiwan will affect that social corporate responsibility
台灣大家都會影響到那個社會企業責任
He talked about something he skipped the reuse process and went straight to the business unit
他所講了一些他跳過這個再利用的流程直接事業單位
After clearing the manufacturer to save the money, it is directly poured over to the extension here.
經過清除廠商省這筆錢直接倒來這邊那延伸的
Some of the resulting problems are bigger and that still can't be solved
衍生的一些問題更大那個還是沒辦法解決
water pollution law
水汙法的話
In the case of water pollution law, if the company wants to expand a factory or build a factory
水汙法的話是如果公司如果要擴一個廠或蓋一個廠房
Will receive some waste water from the site, and if the waste water comes down, there are some heavy metals in the waste water.
都會接收現場的一些廢水下來這些廢水的話有些重金屬
Toxic substances, you have to go through these and need to be treated before they can be discharged. Then you need to set
有害物你要經過這些要經過處理的話才可以去做排放那你要設置的
In the case of a wastewater facility, you need to know these pollutants and whether your facility has enough people to operate it
廢水場的話你要知道這些污染物以及你的設施有沒有足夠的人操作
Then, if it is ok, it is necessary to make regular declarations, including setting up special personnel and water quality.
再來如果ok的話就是要去做定期的申報包括設置專責人員以及水質的
After the automatic monitoring facility is discharged, some regulatory standards must be met
自動監測設施之後排放之後還要合乎一些管制標準
Even if it meets the regulatory standards, he has to pay some water pollution prevention and control fees.
以合乎管制標準就算了還要跟他要繳交一些水污染防治費
As for the wastewater plant, if you do the discharge again, you are prohibited.
那廢水廠的話如果再做排放的動作的話你是有禁止行為
No bypass discharge, no illegal dilution, just use tap water to make sewage
不得繞流排放不得非法稀釋就是拿自來水去做把汙水
It is impossible to reduce the concentration of pollutants inside after dilution.
稀釋完讓裡面汙染物濃度降低這是不行的
Including injection into groundwater bodies and
包括注入地下水體以及
The control area does not have this item in Nanzi Processing Park
管制區在楠梓加工園區是沒有這一項的
And then talk to him is to tell him that before you set up you need to have one
然後再跟他就是要跟他講設立前你要先有一個
You need to submit the water measures plan to the management office and the Environmental Protection Bureau for review.
水措計畫書你要去送審給管理處以及環保局去做送審
Only when the submission is completed can there be some approval documents for water measures and discharge permits
送審完成的時候才可以有一些水措計劃的核准文件以及排放的許可證
Only after these can we set up special personnel, and then we can do the operation and the process of doing the operation.
經過這些才可以去設置專責人員之後就可以去做運作那做運作的過程中
In the production process of the factory, these are all actions that need to be declared.
工廠在生產的過程中這些都是要特定去做申報的動作
The Water Pollution Law cannot. If there are some problems, there will be some regulations.
水汙法無法如果有針對這些問題點就是會有訂一些法規
For example, it is not normal operation such as not exceeding the standard, stealing, diluting, etc.
那例如剛剛所講不能超標偷排獲稀釋等未正常操作
It is impossible to draw 20000000 at the highest level without normal operation
未正常操作畫最高處以20000000何謂處以20000000是不可能因為
Because he will also extend to some waste, because waste water is also equal to waste, he will also
因為他還會延伸到一些廢棄物因為廢水也等於是廢棄物他還會
If you break the law, he will
如果你有違法的話亂排的話他會
Add some rubbish laws to add not only 20000000 for example there is a company near us
追加一些廢棄物的法條加上去不是只有20000000例如我們附近有一家公司
He was already sentenced by the Supreme Court in 2020
他在2020原本是已經的已經被最高法院裁罰
20000000, but in 2020, it will become 40000000 after checking it again. Why because he added the waste item
20000000 但2020又重新再查一次就變成40000000為什麼因為他加了廢棄物這條
If you are like that over the limit
如果你那個像那個超標
There are also some administrative sanctions and some criminal laws. Administrative sanctions are just fines.
還要經過一些行政處分還有一些刑法一樣行政處分就是罰錢而已
If the criminal law is just about to arrest the waste
如果刑法就剛剛跟廢棄物要抓去關
What does it mean to arrest and detain a person from a business unit?
何謂抓去關 事業單位的人
Or the people you discharge are all going to be arrested and detained. The biggest plot is so serious that it makes work or business stop.
或者是你排放的人都是要抓去關的真的還蠻嚴重的最大情節重大得令停工或停業
Closed until when will it open until you improve
停業到什麼時候開業等你整個改善為止
Here are some sketches of the company's water distribution plant
這是公司的配水處理廠的一些簡圖
Then what I just said is that this is the information of the current company
那我剛剛講的就是這是目前公司的那個資料
At that time, the data about some pollution sources that the management office and the Environmental Protection Bureau applied for were:
當時說的跟管理處和環保局申請的一些汙染源的數據是
The following diagrams include PH COD and lead, total chromium, copper, zinc, and nickel.
以下這些圖他有分PH COD的還有鉛總鉻銅鋅鎳
These will be discharged after being treated in our wastewater plant.
這些經過我們的廢水廠處理之後要排放的話要
Comply with the regulatory standards of the park where the discharge is made
遵守排放的那個園區的管制標準
The groundwater that can be discharged to the underground water pipe management office
才可以去排到地下水管管理處的地下水
Then this is from xx company and then
然後這個是xx公司的然後
If you compare this room, you should know that everyone lives nearby. In fact, he discharges
比較對這一間應該知道大家住附近嘛其實他排放
The stagnant stream is actually quite serious, he flowed to that oyster li
後勁溪其實還蠻嚴重的他是流到那個蚵仔寮
Well, this stream, it undertakes CNPC and
那這一條溪它承接中油還有
In the processing area, there is also some waste water in the Dashe Industrial Zone and Renwu Industrial Zone. If your waste water has not been treated properly
加工區還有那個大社工業區還有仁武工業區的一些廢水若如果你廢水沒有處理好
It is directly discharged here, the whole is polluted to the whole river
直接是排放到這邊整個是汙染到整個河川
In fact, their requirement is that what they just said is that the standard discharge is
那其實他們要求就是剛剛所講的是標準排放出去是
It's ok, but if you don't deal with it well, just let it out. This is the picture of Zeppelin seeing Taiwan.
是沒問題但如果你沒有處理好的話直接排放出去整個就是這張是齊柏林看見台灣那張照片
There's a problem with the whole thing. Actually, the stagnant stream looks pretty clean now.
整個都有問題其實現在後勁溪看起來還蠻乾淨
In fact, it is still being rectified. Some pollutants that cannot be seen are left in the soil.
其實還在整頓啦是看不到的一些汙染物都殘留在土壤內
There are rivers and life
還有河川還有生命
Well, I have to wait for that. I have read the literature before, that is, the teacher should see what they are still doing.
那這個要等之前我看過那個文獻就是老師那邊應該看他們還在做那些
The rectification information means that in fact, it takes a hundred recitations to complete the rectification.
整治資料是說其實要整治完還要一百念後
It's okay, don't go fishing there and watch the video
沒事不要去那邊釣魚然後看一下影片吧
Because he is a pipeline for the whole sea
因為他是一個整個海放的管線
It's all long pipes
都是長長的管線
Come this way, all the way here
沿路這樣一路過來到這邊
Finally out to sea
最後出到海裡
This is the last exit to the sea.
這邊是最後的出海口就對了
This is the last vent
這邊是最後的放流口
It's so damn good. Prosecutors are investigating ASE's case of stealing wastewater
實在好可惡檢察官追查日月光偷排廢水案
It was found that the K7 field secretly buried the underground pipe and directly discharged sewage into the sea
發現K7場偷埋暗管直接排放汙水到海裡
The prosecutor went to the k7 factory at night to confirm the location of the hidden pipe and collected the sediment and water from all over the place, and rushed back to the local prosecutor's office for court
檢方夜奔 k7廠確認暗管位置 並採集四處底泥及水漾 在趕回地檢署開庭
Including Su Bingshuo, director of the K7 factory, Cai Qixun, director of the waste water group, and Yan Junming, manager of the wind business department, were interviewed
包括K7廠廠長蘇炳碩 廢水組主任蔡奇勳 風營部經理顏俊明 遭到約談
In addition, the eight K7 factory employees summoned on the evening of the 12th leaked the night investigation and three wastewater discharge operators after 8 hours
此外12號晚間傳喚的8名K7廠員工漏夜偵訊8小時候後三名廢水排放操作人員
They also paid 500,000 to 700,000 yuan on bail. The prosecution also made compulsory punishment for the first time and changed the case to a case investigation.
也各以50到70萬元交保 檢方也首此做出強制處分將案件改為偵字案調查
In addition, the Environmental Protection Agency has also ordered the inspection team in the morning to comprehensively check whether other factories of ASE also have illegal discharge of waste water.
此外環保署上午也已經下令督察總隊全面清查日月光其他廠區是否也有違法排放廢水情事
Once seized, it will suspend work and recover the illegal income in accordance with the practice of Kaohsiung City
一旦查獲將比照高雄市做法 停工並追繳 不法所得
ASE steals waste water from the water surface under the Demin Bridge in Houjinxi, Kaohsiung
日月光偷排自來廢水高雄後勁溪德民橋下的水面
Floating down stream water polluted with carcinogenic toxic heavy metals with a large amount of white chemical foam
漂浮著大量白色化學泡沫內含致癌有毒重金屬污染的溪水往下流
The 940 hectares of farmland downstream may also suffer. The Environmental Protection Bureau of Gao City will trace the source of pollution in October this year.
下游940公頃農田也恐怕都遭殃高市環保局今年10月追查汙染源頭
It was found that the waste water was actually discharged by the world's largest semiconductor packaging and testing factory, the ASE K7 factory
發現這些廢水竟然是由全球最大半導體封測廠日月光k7廠所排放
Chen Jinde, Director of Environmental Protection of Kaohsiung City, personally led a team to inspect the ASE factory yesterday.
高雄市環保局長陳金德昨天親自率隊到日月光廠房稽查
It's really vicious and serious
痛斥日月光兩年來已三次違規做法也不改善真是惡性重大
We last year because we considered that ASE is a big factory
我們去年因為考慮到日月光是大廠
Give him a chance to improve
那麼給他改善的機會
I didn't expect it to be October 1st this year
沒想到今年的10月1號
This is my EPA guy at Demin Bridge
這是我的環保局人員在德民橋
Found someone stealing waste water
發現一個有人偷排廢水
Then trace the source to trace the moonlight
然後追查來源追查到追月光
ASE announced only yesterday that the group's revenue in November was 21.97 billion
日月光昨天才公佈十一月集團營收219.7億
In terms of revenue of 220 billion this year, I did not expect such a large-scale enterprise to illegally discharge wastewater
今年營收上看2200億沒想到如此大規模的企業竟非法排放廢水
Poisoned Kaohsiung City Councillors, Taiwan
毒害台灣高雄市議員痛批日月光家族獨享賺錢成果
Leaving the pollution of the environment to Kaohsiung people is really a sweatshop for the rich and unkind.
把汙染環境留給高雄人承擔實在是血汗工廠為富不仁環保局人員說日月光
Has been found to discharge wastewater and fined many times ASE, so in June last year
已被查獲排放廢水開罰多次日月光因此於去年6月
Installed water quality monitoring equipment but still found that the drainage did not meet the standard and fined 600,000 in October this year
加裝水質監測設備但仍被發現排水不符標準裁罰60萬今年10月
The inspectors also found that the water tank that ASE provided the Environmental Protection Bureau to sample was filled with wastewater diluted with tap water.
稽查人員更發現日月光提供環保局採樣的水槽裡面裝的是自來水稀釋過的廢水
The strong acid wastewater discharged into Houjin Stream is completely untreated strong acid wastewater. Lin Xiantang, deputy general manager of ASE
排入後勁溪卻是完全沒有處理過的強酸廢水日月光副總林顯堂
Yesterday, I was preparing materials to explain to the media, but I was refuted by Chen Jinde before I finished speaking.
昨天還準備資料要向媒體解釋話還沒說完就被陳金德大聲駁斥
The violations are serious and the sophistry is still arguing until now
違規情節重大還狡辯到現在為止還在辯解
did not acknowledge the fact that they deliberately avoided such a fact, so we will
並沒有承認他們的這個蓄意規避的這樣的一個事實那麼所以我們會依
Sewage law imposes heavy fines, otherwise it will order suspension of work
水汙法重罰另外那麼會勒令停工
EPA will fine ASE 600,000
環保局將對日月光開罰60萬
If no valid reason can be presented within 10 days, the K7 factory will be ordered to suspend the production of Kaohsiung farmland water
10天內若無法提出正當理由就勒令K7廠停工高雄農田水
The Water Conservancy Association said that the stinky water of Houjin Stream is the worst farmer in Kaohsiung City's irrigation water.
水利會說後勁溪水有臭味是全高雄市灌溉用水中水質最差的農民
When farmers hear about ASE's waste water, it's terrible, and big tech companies only make money
農民一聽說日月光排廢水大罵真可怕科技大廠難道都只會賺黑心錢
Kaohsiung City Government has invested 3.7 billion in 6 years to remediate the Jinxi River before it has achieved some results
高雄市府6年來投入37億整治後勁溪才稍見成效
And it was destroyed by ASE who secretly drained nickel-containing wastewater. Once the doctor said that nickel is recognized by the World Health Organization
又被日月光偷排含鎳廢水毀於一旦醫師則表示鎳是世界衛生組織認定的
Carcinogen may cause lung cancer, prostate cancer
致癌物可能引發肺癌 攝護腺癌
In the past, the experience of farmland being polluted by heavy metals such as cadmium required a century of fallow
以往農田遭鎘等重金屬污染的經驗都需百年休耕
Only heavy metals in the land can fully decompose ASE denied yesterday
土地中的重金屬才能完全分解日月光昨天否認
Using tap water as a fake for sampling and saying that this is an unusual and unexpected security
以自來水做假供採樣說這是異常純屬應變不及的意外證券
Experts say the shutdown of ASE K7 factory will affect the global supply chain of smartphones, tablets, laptops, etc.
專家說日月光k7廠停工工會影響全球智慧手機平板電腦筆電等供應鏈
He just talked about this thing
這一件事情剛剛他講暗管排偷排
That problem is a bit like our park, his wastewater plant
那個問題點像我們園區啊他的廢水廠
As long as the discharged wastewater will be collected at the oxygen water station of the water raising station management office for collection
只要排出去的廢水都會收集到養水站管理處的氧水站那邊去做收集
The first level will be controlled there. Why does this happen is because of this
第一關會在那邊管控為什麼會發生這一件事是因為這家
The company has applied to Kaohsiung City for a direct discharge to the surface water body, so there is this pipeline.
公司他有去跟高雄市申請一個那個直接排放地面水體所以才有這個管路
In this pipeline, in fact, he has another one, that is, he did not apply directly. This incident is the one who did not apply.
那這管路的話其實他有另外一條就是直接沒有去申請的他這次事件是那個沒有去
I can't get it at the pipeline management office I applied for.
申請的管路管理處那邊完全完全抓不到
Why do you bring this incident out? Because this incident is in Kaohsiung and everyone in Taiwan knows it because
為什麼會把這個事件拿出來因為這個事件是在高雄還有全台灣大家都知道因為
All I have now learned about the largest wastewater plant
全我現在得知了最大的廢水廠
If there is a problem with the wastewater, there will be an abnormality and will be fined.
廢水有問題的話就有異常會被罰款就這1件事最後他
This is the 47 million fined by Kaohsiung City and told him why the highest 20 million went to 47 million
這是高雄市裁罰那個4700萬跟他講最高2000萬為什麼會跑到4700萬
Just because it's covering some of the waste that's because of that nickel row
就是因為它的涵蓋一些廢棄物那些因為排那個鎳
Nickel is also considered a heavy metal in that waste.
鎳在那個廢棄物裡面也算是重金屬的